Guide to the Frost-Lee-Buckingham Family Papers, 1851-1911
Department of Special Collections
Frost-Lee-Buckingham Family Papers,
1851-1911
M0282
Frost Family; Lee Family; Buckingham Family
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Unknown.
Biography
The Frost and Lee Families Papers were created by two families who lived through the Civil War and who united through the marriage of Mary Frost and J.W. Lee.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence and ephemera from the Frost, Lee, and Buckingham Papers. Also includes two essays, one written by a 9 year old child.
The bulk of the correspondence spans 1862 and 1864 and is between Jonathan Wesley Lee and and Mary Frost.
Access Terms
Frost, Mary; Lee, J.W.; Civil War; Frost Family; Lee Family; Buckingham Family; Marriage licenses; Burial plot deed
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Frost Family Papers
  The Frost Family Papers are arranged into two subseries. The first is correspondence arranged chronologically followed by undated and/or partial pieces of correspondence. The second subseries consists of ephemera.
  - Subseries 1. Correspondence, 1867 Jan. 23 - 1911 Jan. 12, n.d.
    - L.C. Frost to Father and Sisters, 1867 Jan. 23
    - Hattie Frost to Sisters, 1867 Mar. 20
    - (L.C. Frost) to Sisters and Father, (1867) June 23
    - Mollie to Friends, 1868 July 5
    - Sarah Frost to Hattie, 1880 Mar. 10
    - Harriet Frost to "Friend", 1883 Mar. 5
    - Rachel to "My dear Sister", 1883 June 10
    - (?) Hattie Frost, 1884 Aug. 20
    - Clara L. Shattuck to "My dear Chautauqua", 1885 Jan. 22
    - [Clara L. Shattuck] to My Dear Friend, 1885 Mar. 11
    - Clara L. Shattuck to Miss Frost, 1885 June 29
    - Clara L. Shattuck to "My Dear Friend", 1885 Sep. 15
    - Hale Jewett to "My Dear Friend", 1907 Jan. 25
    - [Hale Jewett] to "My Dear Friend", 1907 Nov. 17
    - Jennie Heardie (?) to Hattie Frost, 1911 Jan. 12
    - Clara Shattuck to Hattie Frost, n.d.
    - Rachel to her Sisters, n.d.
    - Myrtle Gilmer to (?), n.d.
    - Sarah Frost to Hattie Frost, (?) Jan. 30
    - Hattie Frost to her Sister, n.d.
    - Sarah Frost to (?), (?) Feb. 17
  - Subseries 2. Ephemera, n.d.
    - Envelope addressed to Lizzie Frost
    - Christmas Card (handwritten by (?).L. Frost)
    - Clipping. J.C. Clark obituary
    - Essay by Myrtle when 9 years old
    - Burial Plot Deed. Sarah Frost
- Series 2. Buckingham Family Papers
  Contains three pieces of correspondence and one essay.
  - A.L. Buckingham to her Brother, 1851 Mar. 9
  - A.L. Buckingham to Henry, 1851 Aug. 17
  - L.B. to "Brother", 1851 Oct. 19
  - Essay by Bessie L. Buckingham, "The Picket Guard"n.d.
- Series 3. Lee Family Papers
  The Lee Family Papers are subdivided into three subseries. Subseries 1 contains correspondence to and from various members of the Lee Family. Subseries 2 contains Lee Family ephemera. Subseries 3 contains correspondence from J. Wesley Lee during the Civil War.
  - Subseries 1. Correspondence, 1858 July 27 - 1911 Dec. 28, n.d.
    - Tho.(?) John W. Lee (Uncle to Nephew), 1858 July 27
    - Tho. Lee to John W. Lee, 1858 July 29
    - (?) to John, 1859 Feb. 22
    - J. Laycock to Nephew [J.W. Lee], 1859 Sept. 1
    - Tho. Lee to Nephew, 1860 Aug. 2
    - Lizzie to Neice, 1883 Aug. 12
    - (?) to Mrs. M.A. Lee, (190?) Nov. 10
    - Mary S. Mathews to Mrs. Lee, 1911 Dec. 28
    - Mary A. Lee to Mrs. Hatfield, n.d.
  - Subseries 2. Ephemera, n.d.
    - Statement of marriage. J. W. Lee to Mary A. Frost signed by John G. Gilmer, n.d.
    - Unkown letter, n.d.
  - Subseries 3. Letters from John Wesley Lee during the Civil War, 1859 Mar. [8?] - 1864 June 23, 1908 May 5
    - Jonathan Wesley Lee to Mary frost, 1859 Mar. 8(?)
    - [W.L.] to Molly, 1860 Oct. 15
    - W.L. to wife, 1862 Mar. 8
    - W.L. to wife, 1862 Apr. 23
    - [W.L. to wife], 1862 June 18
    - W.L. to wife, 1862 July 11
    - Mollie to husband, 1862 Sept. 16
    - W.L. to wife, 1862 Oct. 9
    - W.L. to wife, 1862 Oct. 9
    - [W.L.] to wife, 1862 Oct. 13
    - W.L. to wife, 1862 Nov. 10
    - W.L. to wife, [1862]Nov. 28
    - W.L. to wife, 1862 Dec. 3
    - W.L. to wife, 1863 Apr. 6
    - W.L. to wife, 1863 May 16
    - W.L. to wife, 1863 May 20
    - W.L. to wife, 1863 June 8
    - W.L. to wife, 1863 June 21
    - W.L. to wife, 1863 July 4
    - W.L. to wife, 1863 Dec. 24
    - [W.L.] to wife, 1864 Apr. 30
    - W.L. to wife, 1864 May 11
    - W.L. to wife, 1864 May 20
    - W.L. to "My Dear Girl" [Wife], 1864 May 24
    - W.L. to wife, 1864 May 27
    - W.L. to "My Dear Girl" [Wife], 1864 June 13
    - W.L. to [Wife], 1864 June 21
    - W.L. to wife, 1864 June 23
    - Brother John to Mollie, 1908 May 4
    - Presentation of Flag to the 32nd Regiment n.d.